#### **SHALINI SUNKURU**

Candidate for: Front-end Development

Norwich | (0)7424686926 | <a href="mailto:sunkuru@gmail.com">shalini.sunkuru@gmail.com</a> | <a href="mailto:www.linkedin.com/in/shalini-sunkuru/">www.linkedin.com/in/shalini-sunkuru</a> <a href="https://github.com/ShaliniSunkuru/">https://github.com/ShaliniSunkuru/</a>

#### SUMMARY

Software engineer with 4+ years of experience in C# .Net and SAP ABAP at Wipro and Xchanging Technologies and in software testing at Finz, a London-based Fintech start-up. Worked in an agile product development life cycle. Have a good knowledge of basic Java and Python and confident in front-end technologies including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, and React. Currently attending a 16-week skills bootcamp in front-end web development.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, Jest, React, Software testing, Python, Java, C# .Net, SAP ABAP, JIRA, Zephyr, Confluence

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SKILLS BOOTCAMP IN FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT

2023 to Present

- Learning front-end web development, including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, and GitHub.
- Learning how to use JavaScript frameworks to leverage and manipulate data via application programming interfaces (APIs), including web APIs and RESTful APIs.
- Learning Node.js for creation of server-side web applications and React for building UI components.

# **UAT ANALYST, FINZ, London**

2022 to 2023

- Worked with the product team and led the quality assurance in product development.
- Prepared product/feature spec.
- Created test cases and test cycles for the Finz mobile app using JIRA Zephyr while working in an agile software development life cycle.
- Regularly executed test cycles and tracked defects in periodic releases to ensure all the integrated functionalities worked as expected.
- Created and executed API test plans using Postman.
- Documented clear and concise bug reports that included screenshots and screen recordings and worked with the development team to fix them.

#### FREELANCE TECHNICAL AND CONTENT WRITER

2016 to 2021

• Provided high-quality technical and content writing/editing services to clients and start-ups mostly in the UK and USA.

TEAM MANAGER, CONTENT, WEAVING THOUGHTS, Delhi

2015 to 2016

- Managed a team of content writers from UK, USA, Australia, and New Zealand, distributing work according to the different time-zones.
- Ensured all content confirmed to clients' requirement, was of good quality and was delivered within deadlines.

#### CONTENT WRITER AND EDITOR, WEAVING THOUGHTS, Delhi

2013 to 2015

- Created content in the form of web pages, blogs, and rewrites for clients across the world in software, technology, health, and other niches.
- Ensured content was unique, grammatically superior, and well within deadlines.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, XCHANGING, Gurgaon

2010 to 2013

- Created and maintained technical and development specifications.
- Worked on Xchanging's product, Genius, an end-to-end property and casualty insurance solution for policy and claims.
- Used C# .Net and SQL Server in Visual Studio 2008 for Genius product development requirements.
- Resolved issues in code by debugging and following better coding practices.

#### PROJECT ENGINEER, WIPRO, Hyderabad

2009 to 2010

- Worked as an Associate SAP ABAP Consultant.
- Created and maintained technical design documents.
- Developed programs in ABAP in the HR and SRM modules.

## LECTURER, VSSUT, BURLA, INDIA

2008 to 2009

- Taught the theory subjects: Computer Science, Mathematical Methods, and Production Management to 3<sup>rd</sup> year and Final year B.Tech students.
- Managed practical sessions in Simulation laboratory using MATLAB, and AutoCAD.

### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Technology in Manufacturing Science and Engineering at University College of Engineering, Burla, India Scored a CGPA of 8.29, was the topper of the batch.
- Scored 90.6 percent in Class XII (equivalent to A-Levels in the UK).
- Scored 87.6 percent in Class X (equivalent to GCSE in the UK).

# **COURSES**

- Skills bootcamp in Front-end Web Development, edX
- Introduction to Programming with Python and Java Specialization by the University of Pennsylvania, on Coursera
- Pursuing the course, Selenium 4 WebDriver with Java (Basics + Advanced + Architect) by Rahul Arora, on Udemy.
- Attended a course on Core Java at NIIT Ltd, India
- Attended training in CAD/CAM at Central Tool Room and Training Centre (CTTC), Bhubaneswar,
  India

### **OTHER ACTIVITIES**

- Passionate in poetry writing; got published in an anthology of poems, Roots and Wings and in several e-zines like Simply Haiku and World Haiku Review.
- Certified in Indian Classical vocal music.